Guide to the Geochemical Data Collection
University of Houston Libraries
Geochemical Data Collection
1944-1975
2011-016
University of Houston. Libraries. Special Collections Department
43.00 Items
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
Collection of 43 geochemical data maps from locations in Texas, Louisiana, Mississippi, Florida, Kentucky, and Israel.
Historical Note:
Special Collections collects and preserves historically significant materials. Its holdings comprise a rare book collection and ten main archival collecting areas. In some instances, Special Collections gathers materials on a single topic to preserve them and make them available. In these cases, Special Collections is seen as the creator of the artificially constructed collection.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Maps (documents)
Acquisition Information:
Anonymous donation
Conditions Governing Access:
** As a condition to any use of any document in this collection, all users agree to and acknowledge the following:
No warranty or representation of any kind, express, implied or statutory, is made with respect to the condition, quality, reliability, completeness or accuracy of this document and the geochemical or other information, data, and interpretations contained herein. This document and the geochemical or other information, data, and interpretations contained herein are provided "as is, where is" with all faults and without any warranty or representation of any kind whatsoever, including but not limited to any implied warranty of merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose, suitability for intended use or otherwise, all of which are completely disclaimed. No owner or previous owner of this document or the information contained herein shall be liable in any way for any cost, loss, expense or inconvenience resulting from the use of and/or reliance upon the same (such use and/or reliance being at the user's own risk). Any use of or reference to this document constitutes an acknowledgement of and agreement to these terms and conditions.
Scope and Contents
Collection of 43 geochemical data maps from locations in Texas, Louisiana, Mississippi, Florida, Kentucky, and Israel between 1944 and 1975, with most maps from the 1940s to 1960s. Within the collection are maps for methane, ethane and heavier hydrocarbons, pentane, soil gas, sand percent, ethane and propane and butane, and total hydrocarbons.
Detailed List of Contents
- Geochemical Data, Offshore
  - Areas A, AF, AN, AW, and A2, North Sea, 1974-1975 (Drawer F.6, Folder 1)
    Samples collected July 10, 1974 to July 16, 1974 and December 30, 1974 to January 6, 1975. Total of 387 sampled points. The set of paper maps includes four maps: (1) Methane Map, (2) Ethane and Heavier Hydrocarbons Map, (3) Pentane Map, and (4) Sand Percent Map.**
- Geochemical Data, Onshore
  - Oberlin Area, Allen Parish, Louisiana, N.d. (Drawer F.6, Folder 2)
    Unknown sample collection date. Total of 373 sampled points. The set of paper maps includes two maps: (1) Methane Map, and (2) Ethane and Heavier Hydrocarbons Map.**
  - Gilmer Area, Upshur County, Texas, 1968 (Drawer F.6, Folder 3)
    Samples collected September, 1968. Total of 250 sampled points. The set of paper maps includes one map: (1) Soil Gas Map.**
  - Anderson Area, Grimes County, Texas, 1948-1949 (Drawer F.6, Folder 4)
    Samples collected February, 1948 to April, 1948 and December, 1948 to January, 1949. Total of 758 sampled points. The set of paper maps includes two maps: (1) Ethane Map, and (2) Methane Map.**
  - Delhi Area, Richland and Franklin Parishes, Louisiana, 1946 (Drawer F.6, Folder 5)
    Samples collected March 19, 1946 to June 5, 1946. Total of 429 sampled points. The set of paper maps includes two maps: (1) Total Hydrocarbons Map, and (2) Sand Percent Map.**
  - High Island Area, Galveston County, Texas, 1968 (Drawer F.6, Folder 6)
    Samples collected August, 1968 to September, 1968. Total of 208 sampled points. The set of paper maps includes six maps: (1) Methane Map, (2) Soil Gas (surface) Map, (3) Soil Gas (3') Map, (4) Soil Gas (6') Map, (5) Soil Gas (9') Map, and (6) Ethane and Heavier Hydrocarbons Map.**
  - Gageby Creek Area, Wheeler County, Texas, 1962-1963 (Drawer F.6, Folder 7)
    Samples collected October, 1962 to April, 1963. Total of 285 sampled points. The set of paper maps includes two maps: (1) Methane Map, and (2) Ethane and Heavier Hydrocarbons Map.**
  - Vealmoor Oil Field, Borden and Howard Counties, Texas, 1950 (Drawer F.6, Folder 8)
    Samples collected January, 1950 to February, 1950. Total of 405 sampled points. The set of paper maps includes two maps: (1) Methane Map, and (2) Ethane and Heavier Hydrocarbons Map.**
  - Heidelberg Oil Field, Jasper County, Mississippi, N.d. (Drawer F.6, Folder 9)
    Unknown sample collection date. Total of 356 sampled points. The set of paper maps includes three maps: (1) Methane Map, (2) Ethane and Heavier Hydrocarbons Map, and (3) Total Hydrocarbons Map.**
  - Sunniland Oil Field, Collier County, Florida, 1951 (Drawer F.6, Folder 10)
    Samples collected August, 1951 to September, 1951. Total of 72 sampled points. The set of paper maps includes two maps: (1) Ethane and Heavier Hydrocarbons Map, and (2) Methane Map.**
  - Edmundton Area, Metcalfe County, Kentucky (Drawer F.6, Folder 11)
    Unknown sample collection date. Total of 46 sampled points. The set of paper maps includes three maps: (1) Pentane Map, (2) Methane Map, and (3) Ethane and Propane and Butane Map.**
  - Midfield, Blessing, Tri-counties, and Danevang Areas, Matagorda and Jackson Counties, Texas, 1944-1945, 1954, 1971 (Drawer F.6, Folder 12)
    Samples collected April, 1944 to April, 1945, May, 1954 to June, 1954 and May, 1971 to June, 1971. Total of 711 sampled points. The set of paper maps includes four maps: (1) Methane Map (sampled 1944, 1945, and 1954), (2) Ethane and Heavier Hydrocarbons Map (sampled 1944, 1945, and 1954), (3) Methane Map (sampling supplemented in 1971), and (4) Ethane and Heavier Hydrocarbons Map (sampling supplemented in 1971).**
  - Lapice-Napoleonville Area, Ascension, St. James and Assumption Parishes, Louisiana, 1964-1966 (Drawer F.6, Folder 13)
    Samples collected September, 1964 to November, 1964 and May, 1965 to March, 1966. Total of 1475 sampled points. The set of paper maps includes two maps: (1) Methane Map, and (2) Iso-Pentane Map.**
  - Cranfield Area, Adams and Franklin Counties, Mississippi, 1945 (Drawer F.6, Folder 14)
    Samples collected March, 1945. Total of 356 sampled points. The set of paper maps includes three maps: (1) Ethane and Heavier Hydrocarbons Map, (2) Methane Map, and (3) Total Hydrocarbons Map.**
  - Nelta Area, Hopkins County, Texas, 1966 (Drawer F.6, Folder 15)
    Samples collected May, 1966 to September, 1966. Total of 740 sampled points. The set of paper maps includes three maps: (1) Ethane and Propane and Butane Map, (2) Methane Map, and (3) Pentane Map.**
  - Beit Guvrin Area, Israel, 1965 (Drawer F.6, Folder 16)
    Samples collected April, 1965 to November, 1965. Total of 2269 sampled points. The set of paper maps includes two maps: (1) Ethane and Propane and Butane Map, and (2) Methane Map.**